# MOHD AZAM ANSARI

Front-end developer with 3 years of experience in designing and building responsive web design in the financial industry. Proficient with CSS and JS Frameworks, with extensive knowledge of UX and User psychology. Notable achievements include boosting the conversion rate of an existing website by 80% with improved code and design.

☑ techazamansari@gmail.com

**\** 7906079480

Noida

in mohd-azam-ansari-578b4816b

https://portfolio-git-master-mohd-azam-ansaris-projects.vercel.app/

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **NTT Data Buisness Solutions**

HTML Web Developer

Jul 2024 - Present

- Created interactive invoices with jQuery, HTML, CSS, XHTML, XSLFO, Java and XSLT resulting in improved user experience maintained 98. 6% average client satisfaction score across all projects, well above industry average.
- Used version control effectively to manage codebase and implement bug fixes.
- Implemented efficiency enhancement strategies which led to 15% better performance.

#### **Island Beach Vacation**

Frontend Developer

Jan 2022 - Feb 2024

- Designed a new, user interactive landing page, utilizing tools like React.js, HTML, Tailwind, Bootstrap, jQuery, CSS, etc. achieving a 5.5/6 user score. Ensure websites are mobile-friendly and work across various devices and screen sizes
- Boosted the conversion rate by 80% by improving the design. Identify and fix bugs, and conduct thorough testing to ensure functionality across different browsers and devices.

# **EDUCATION**

#### **Dr APJ Abdul Kalam Technical University**

Bachelor Of Engineering - 7.0

Aug 2015 - May 2018

# **PROJECT**

**ICBC Standard Bank** 

Jul 2024 - Present

- Developed customer facing invoices from scratch using jQuery, HTML, CSS, XSLFO, XHTML, XSLT, Java boosting user satisfaction score by 20%.
- Enhanced system accessibility and responsiveness, leading to 10% increase in daily user.

Pure It Water Jan 2023 - Feb 2024

- Developing a high-performance single-page application using React, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap reducing load times by 30%.
- Implemented responsive and accessible design, ensuring compatibility across multiple devices and browsers, boosting user engagement by 25%.

Wolseley UK Jan 2022 - Dec 2022

- Pioneered the use of modern web frameworks and libraries, increasing development efficiency and reducing time to market by 18%.
- Engineered a complex web system application software that increased customer conversion rates by 12%.

## **SKILLS**

- Programming: JavaScript
- Front-end: React.js, jQuery, HTML, Tailwind, Bootstrap, CSS
- · Backend: Node.js, Express.js, RESTful API
- Tools: Git, npm, yarn